Finding Aid for the Bennet Harvive Branscomb Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Incoming Correspondence Index
  Hardie, Frances, (1); Sept. 26, 1975; F 33.
  Haussamen, Crane, (1); Mar. 26, 1964 (Airgram addressed to Dept, of State); F 26.
  Hays, Brooks, (1); Nov. 7, 1969, Dec. 17, 1969, n.d.; F 19.
  Hazlehurst, F. Hamilton, (1); Sept. 21, 1967; F 23.
  Heard, Alexander, (5); Mar. 2, 1964 (addressed to Mrs. Preston Davie); F 21; Mar. 6, 1965 (addressed to Harold S. Vanderbilt), Mar. 18, 1965 (addressed to Harold S. Vanderbilt); F 35; Nov. 8, 1965 (addressed to Robert K. Carr), Nov. 18, 1965 (memorandum to conmittee on Relationships between the Divinity School and Oberlin College); F 33.
  Hester, James M., (1); Oct. 1, 1973; F 15.
  Hicks, Henry D., (1); Apr. 28, 1964; F 26.
  Hill, Lister, (1); Mar. 30, 1964; F 7.
  Hliddal, Freda T., (4); Sept. 28, Oct. 20, 1970, Oct. 11, Nov. 11, 1973; F 15.
  Hobson, Jesse E., (12); June 27, July 2, Aug. 11, Aug. 12, 1969 (addressed to Dr. Joseph F. Volker), Aug. 15, Sept. 5, Nov. 11, 1969, Feb. 9, Feb. 19, Mar. 16, Apr. 3, June 6, 1970; F 16.
  Hoffman, Paul G.; (1); Apr. 22, 1964; F 26.
  Houle, Cyril 0., (1); Jan. 20, 1964; F 26.
  Houston, Frank K., (1); July 2, 1973; F 33.
  Hughes, Edwin, (1); June 24, 1964; F 26.
  Humelsine, Carlisle H., (3); Nov. 25, 1953 (addressed to Mr. Chorley), Apr. 1, 1963; F 6; Jan. 8, 1964; F 26.
  Hummel, Arthur W., Jr., (1); Mar. 31, 1965; F 27.
  Hyatt, Carl B., (9); Mar. 23, Oct. 19, Nov. 21, 1966, Dec. 14, 1967, May 15, June 21, 1968 (telegram), Oct. 8, 1968, Feb. 19, 1969, Feb. 19, 1969 (addressed to Justice Clark); F 19.
  J
  James, Pauline, (1); Jan. 13, 1969; F 20.
  Jewell, Willard B., (1); Oct. 14, 1961 (addressed to Henry C. Alexander with enclosure); F 32.
  Johnson, Lyndon B., (2); Sept. 8, 1965, n.d.; F 27.
  Johnson, William C., (1); Apr. 25, 1949; F 29.
  Joja, Athanase, (2); Apr. 30, Dec. 1, 1965 (telegram); F 27.
  Jones, James A., (1); Dec. 2, 1960; F 34.
  Jonsson, J.E., (2); Mar. 6, Mar. 26, 1963; F 17.
  Jordan, Constance, (1); Apr. 27, 1970 (addressed to Bernard Werthan, also signed by Anna M. Wilson); F 31.
  Judson, Sheldon, (2); Dec. 16, 1964, Jan. 29, 1965 (addressed to members BAEF - also signed by George Wickes); F 9.
  K
  Karp, Basil, (1); Apr. 27, 1965; F 27.
  Karp, Robert E., (1); Oct. 18, 1967; F 18.
  Kelley, Robert W., Sr., (1); July 29, 1970; F 31.
  Keppel, Francis, (1); Dec. 20, 1963; F 26.
  Kern, Paul B., (1); Oct. 11, 1946; F 3.
  Kidd, Charles V., (1); Mar. 12, 1964; F 30.
  Kimpton, Lawrence A., (2); June 21, 1966, Nov. 10, 1967; F 21.
  King, Helen S., (2); Mar. 12, 1965, Dec. 28, 1965; F 9.
  Kirk, Grayson, (2); June 24, 1963, Apr. 3, 1965; F 2.
  Kissick, William L., (3); Aug. 18, 1966, Apr. 19, 1967, Sept. 18, 1967; F 25.
  Kohn, Clyde F., (1); Sept. 23, 1965; F 27.
  Kotschnig, Walter, (1); Nov. 17, 1964 (addressed to Senator Benton); F 26.
  Kubler, George, (1); Oct. 5, 1964 (addressed to L.A. Minnich); F 26.
  L
  Larson, Arthur, (1); Aug. 29, 1964; F 26.
  Laves, Walter H.C., (1); Dec. 22, 1964; F 26.
  Leavitt, Milo David, (1); Dec. 17, 1964; F 30.
  Leestman, Robert, (1); June 22, 1967; F 22.
  Lester, Robert M., (1); Dec. 27, 1961; F 32.
  Lewis, Cotesworth P., (1); Oct. 25, 1963; F 10.
  Liebaers, Herman, (1); Nov. 21, 1966; F 9.
  Livingston, Robert B., (1); May 11, 1964; F 30.
  Lowe, Pardee, (2); May 2, May 12, 1967; F 22.
  Lyle, Robert S., (8); May 27, 1963, Mar. 25, Aug. 18, 1964, Jan. 4, Jan. 11, Jan. 26, Feb. 5, 1965; F 17; Apr. 7, 1967; F 27.
  M
  MacArthur, Douglas, II, (2); May 27, 1965 (addressed to Senator Robinson), June 22, 1965; F 27.
  MacBeth, Russell, (1); June 16, 1970 (addressed to Thomas L. Cummings, Jr.); F 23.
  McClellan, James F., (2); June 23, 1970, Dec. 3, 1970; F 31.
  McClurry, Forrest, (1); Dec. 14, 1965; F 27.
  McGaw, Robert A. (1); June 7, 1973; F 33.
  McGee, Gale, (1); Apr. 8, 1964; F 26.
  McGugin, Dan E., Jr., (1); May 30, 1962 (addressed to Henry C. Alexander); F 32.
  MacLeish, Archibald, (1); Feb. 17 (?); F 26.
  Macomber, William B., Jr., (1); June 1, 1965 (addressed to William W. Marvel); F 13.
  McPherson, Harry C., Jr., (5); Oct. 16, 1964; F 7; Jan. 18, Apr. 12, June 1, Aug. 11, 1965; F 27.
  Macy, John W., Jr., (1); June 7, 1965 (addressed to Ellis Arnall); F 27.
  Maheu, Rene, (4); (1964, addressed to Paul J. Braisted), July 16, 1964; F 26; Dec. 31, July 15, 1965 (telegram); F 27.
  Marvel, William W., (3); May 13, June 15, 1965, June 15, 1965 (addressed to William B. Macomber, Jr.); F 13.
  Mezoff, Earl R., (1); Oct. 10, 1978; F 25.
  Miller, Alfred, (1); May 7, 1962; F 32.
  Miller, Charles, (1); Oct. 9, 1968; F 31.
  Miller, Watson B., (1); Mar. 31, 1949 (addressed to George V. Allen); F 29.
  Minnich, L.A., (12); Dec. 9, 1963, Feb. 27, 1964 (addressed to Archibald MacLeish), Apr. 8, 1964 (addressed to Lawrence M.C. Smith), June 26, 1964, Sept. 29, 1964 (addressed to George Kubler), Nov. 20, 1964 (addressed to Robert H.B. Wade), Dec. 18, 1964; F 26; Jan. 4, 1965 (addressed to Mrs. Lawrence M.G. Smith), Oct. 27, 1965 (addressed to Thomas F. Malone), Jan. 7, 1966 (addressed to Wladyslaw Grzedzielski), Apr. 18, 1966, Nov. 7, 1967; F 27.
  Mitchell, Sidney A., (1); June 22, 1965 (addressed to Prof. E.J. Bigwood); F 9.
  Moon, Rexford G., Jr., (3); Jan. 9, 1969; F 4; Feb. 26, 1969; F 20; Jan. 8, 1970; F 4.
  Moses, Robert, (1); Mar. 19, 1973; F 15.
  Murdock, Richard C., (1); July 14, 1965 (addressed to E.E. Bryan); F 35.
  N
  Neese, C.G., (6); June 10, June 28, Nov. 1, Nov. 15, 1976, Feb. 25, Mar. 8, 1977; F 25.
  Nelson, Allan, (1); Oct. 21, 1965; F 27.
  Nelson, J. Robert, (4); Aug. 20, Dec. 25, 1960, May 21, June 6, 1963; F 34.
  Nguyen-Dinh-Hoa, (1); Feb. 8, 1964; F 26.
  Nicholson, (1); Apr. 29, 1949; F 29.
  Niles, Russell Denison, (9); Nov. 1, 1970, Sept. 17, Dec. 14, 1971, June 9, 1972, June 12, 1973 (telegram), May 31, June 1, June 15, Sept. 14, 1973; F 15.
  P
  Pahl, Herbert B., (3); July 9, Aug. 4, 1964, Sept. 8, 1965; F 30.
  Pecson, Geronima T., (1); July 27, 1964; F 26.
  Peele, W.W., (1); Oct. 11, 1946; F 3.
  Perinbam, Lewis, (1); Mar. 4, 1964 (addressed to L.A. Minnich); F 26.
  Phillips, Richard I., (1); May 18, 1966; F 22.
  Platt, William, (2); Sept. 4, 1964, Feb. 5, 1965; F 35.
  Powell, Lewis, (1); Nov. 22, 1965; F 10.
  Prakasha, Veda, (2); Oct. 13, Oct. 17, 1964; F 26.
  Price, Charles C., (1); Apr. 10, 1964; F 26.
  Price, Don, (3); Dec. 20, 1961, Feb. 4, 1962 (addressed to Henry C. Alexander), Feb. 17, 1962 (addressed to Henry C. Alexander); F 32.
  Q
  Ouarterman, Elsie, (1); Aug. 17, 1967; F 23.
  Quero-Chiesa, Luis, (1); Feb. 13, 1967; F 15.
  R
  Reams, Elinor P., (2); Mar. 17, 1949 (addressed to Mr. Linton), Nov. 1, 1950; F 29.
  Reisman, S. John, (1); Mar. 18, 1964; F 30.
  Riddle, Rebecca, (1); Oct. 2, 1967; F 23.
  Robertson, Cathy, (1); Mar. 1, 1966 (addressed to Mary Irvine); F 30.
  Rosenfeld, Barbara, (1); Feb. 12, 1964; F 26.
  Rowson, Richard C., (1); Feb. 28, 1962; F 32.
  Rusk, Dean, (3); Jan. 26, Apr. 27, 1965, Dec. 18, 1967; F 27.
  S
  Sands, Paul, (1); Aug. 29, 1977; F 24.
  Sargent, Howland H., (1); Oct. 19, 1948; F 29.
  Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., (1); Dec. 2, 1963; F 26.
  Schwenkmeyer, Barry, (1); Oct. 2, 1968; F 4.
  Scott, Gordon, (2); Mar. 8, 1965, July 23, 1967; F 23.
  Seidman, P.K., (1); Feb. 8, 1968; F 14.
  Shannon, James A., (2); Sept. 17, 1965, Jan. 4, 1966; F 30.
  Sharp, Walter, (1); Apr. 15, 1965 (addressed to R.D. Stanford, Jr.); F 23.
  Shayne, May W., (1); May 30, 1977; F 3.
  Shine, D. Bruce, (1); Oct. 28, 1976; F 25.
  Shulman, Herbert L., (1); Aug. 9, 1976; F 25.
  Shuster, George N., (1); Nov. 18, 1963; F 26.
  Silberman, Lou H., (1); June 16, 1960; F 34.
  Sisco, Joseph J., (1); Aug. 18, 1965; F 27.
  Sockman, Ralph W., (2); Oct. 26, 1964, June 1, 1970; F 15.
  Smith, Lawrence M.C., (3); May 12, 1964; F 26; Mar. 25, 1965 (addressed to to Harry C. McPherson), June 18, 1965; F 27.
  Smith, William S., (1); Nov. 1, 1968; F 31.
  Smythe, Mrs. Hugh H., (1); Dec. 26, 1964 (addressed to Robert H.B. Wade); F 26.
  Spivacke, Harold, (1); July 2, 1964; F 26.
  Starabaugh, John H., (1); May 30, 1962 (addressed to Harold Vanderbilt); F 32.
  Stanford, R.D., (1); May 5, 1965; F 23.
  Steele, Thomas Wardlaw, (1); Sept. 5, 1967; F 23.
  Stevenson, Eldon, Jr., (1); Oct. 19, 1971 (addressed to Henry C. Alexander); F 32.
  Stevenson, William E., (2); Oct. 20, Nov. 17, 1967; F 6.
  Stewart, Ella Phillips, (1); Aug. 9, 1965; F 27.
  Stewart, William H., (4); Jan. 24, June 27, Oct. 7, 1966, Sept. 8, 1967; F 30.
  Sumner, Billy T., (6); June 24, Sept. 21, 1967, Nov. 21, 1967 (telegram), Nov. 27, 1967, May 28, 1968 (addressed to Neil Bass, Robert L. Gwinn, Robert Street, Charles Waterfield, with copy of May 14, 1968 letter to Sumner), Apr. 16, 1969 (addressed to Thomas Cunmings, Jr.); F 23.
  T
  Tax, Sol, (1); Feb. 3, 1964 (addressed to Lawrence M.C. Smith); F 26.
  Terry, Luther, (4); Jan. 27, Feb. 3, 1964; F 25; June 4, 1965; F 37; July 1, July 30, 1965; F 30.
  Tickton, Sidney G., (3); Apr. 13, 1964, Mar. 15, 1965, Aug. 3, 1965; F 4.
  Tirrill, Bess B., (1); Sept. 14, 1967; F 23.
  Torrey, Clare M., (7); Mar. 24, Dec. 17, 1964, Jan. 13, Dec. 15, Dec. 28, Jan. 13, 1965, Nov. 3, 1967; F 9.
  Trabue, Charles C., Jr., (2); May 10, 1962 (addressed to Harold S. Vanderbilt), June 22, 1962; F 32.
  Treadway, Cleo, (1); Feb. 1, 1977; F 25.
  Tuck, W. Hallam, (1); Jan. 29, 1965; F 9.
  Turner, H. Chandlee, Jr., (1); Nov. 20, 1965; F 10.
  Turner, Olive G., (1); Apr. 25, 1964; F 26.
  V
  Van Alen Holloman, (2); Sept. 16, 1964, Jan. 27, 1965; F 17.
  Vanderbilt, Harold S., (5); July 31, 1961, June 18, 1962; F 32; Mar. 10, 1965 (addressed to Alexander Heard), Mar. 22, 1965 (addressed to Alexander Heard), Sept. 10, 1965 (addressed to Alexander Heard); F 35.
  Van der Eycken, Henri, (3); July 28, 1965 (addressed to Harry Bober); July 28, 1965 (addressed to Clare M. Torrey), Nov. 9, 1965 (addressed to Clare M. Torrey); F 9.
  Voss, Thomas G., (6); Sept. 6, Sept. 20, Dec. 28, 1976, Apr. 22, Oct. 12, 1977, May 17, 1978; F 25.
  W
  Wade, Robert H.B., (1); Jan. 6, 1965; F 27.
  Walker, Charles R., (3); Sept. 27, 1968, July 11, Nov. 3, 1969; F 31.
  Waller, William, (1); May 23, 1950; F 33.
  Walsh, George J., (1); May 13, 1965; F 27.
  West, Margaret D., (3); Apr. 26, Sept. 21, 1966, Feb. 24, 1967; F 30.
  Williams, Clanton W., (1); Mar. 16, 1965; F 13.
  Williams, M.D., (1); Sept. 10, 1969; F 31.
  Wilson, Logan, (1); Dec. 10, 1963; F 26.
  Wilson, 0. Meredith, (1); Dec. 20, 1963; F 26.
  Woods, George D., (1); July 9, 1963; F 36.
  Wright, Henry L., (1); Sept. 23, 1965; F 27.
  Y
  Young, Dora E., (1); Dec. 13, 1948; F 3.
- Correspondence - Outgoing. Feb. 7, 1929 - Oct. 31, 1978. Outgoing correspondence arranged chronologically by year, month and day. Letters are holograph, typescript, printed, photocopies and carbon copies. Includes memoranda. There are 4 undated letters. See Outgoing Correspondence Index., 1 (Folder 1-2)
- Correspondence - Incoming (Miscellaneous). 6 holograph and typescript letters pertaining to various subjects. (All other incoming correspondence is filed according to appropriate subject, but listed alphabetically by author. See Incoming Correspondence Index)., 1 (Folder 3)
- Academy for Educational Development. Correspondence., 1 (Folder 4)
- Reports and agendas: Advisory Committee on the Consortium of Universities of the Washington Metropolitan Area, July 17, 1968; Coordinating Council for Higher Education, Resolution; Detroit Institute of Technology-Today, Tomorrow, and in the Generation Ahead; Educational Trends in Certain Professional Schools in the State of Pennsylvania; Innovations in Undergraduate Education; Major Issues to be Faced in Planning the Future of Higher Education; Faculty Development at Tuskegee Institute; A New Approach to Undergraduate Education; Program of Study of the International University for Independent Study; Proposed Establishment of the International University for Independent Study; A Proposed Program for Undergraduate Instruction; Recommendations; Summary of Staff Findings and Recommendations regarding the Structure and Governance of Higher Education; University of Redlands report. Newspaper clippings., 5 (Folder 3)
- American Association of Colleges Conference on the Humanities. Correspondence., 1 (Folder 6)
- American Committee to Preserve Abu Simbel. Correspondence, lists of committee.members., 1 (Folder 7)
- American Council on Education. Reports: Commission on Education and International Affairs; Conference on the Cultural Relations of the United States and the Soviet Union., 1 (Folder 8)
- Belgian-American Educational Foundation. Correspondence. American Association of C.R.B. Alumni, Inc.: Press release, amended complaint. Historical summary. Lists of members and directors. President's report on lawsuit brought by George Wickes and S. Sheldon Judson, Jr. Newspaper clippings., 1 (Folder 9)
- Colonial Williamsburg. Correspondence. Printed raaterials-brochure, broadsides, map. Board of Trust minutes, lists of trustees and directors., 1 (Folder 10)
- Commission on the Humanities of the ACLS. List of participants in the Worcester Conference. Reports: The Graduate School Today and Tomorrow. The Place of Teaching in the Humanities., 1 (Folder 11)
- Cordell Hull Foundation for International Education. Correspondence. Ballot, contract proposal, and financial statements., 1 (Folder 12)
- Education and World Affairs. Correspondence. Reports: Report on Mission to India, March 12-28, 1965. Report on Summer Institute Follow-Up Program. Trip itinerary, holograph notes. "International Education Act of 1966" bill., 1 (Folder 13)
- Foundation for Better Government for Tennessee. Correspondence. Reports: Board of Trust meeting, resolution. Summary of proposals to amend the Constitution of Tennessee. Lists of members of committee., 2 (Folder 14)
- Hall of Fame for Great Americans. Correspondence. Lists of members, agenda, resolution, rules, minutes of board meeting., 2 (Folder 15)
- Heald. Hobson and Associates, Incorporated. Correspondence. Agendas, lists of advisors., 2 (Folder 16)
- Hockaday School. Correspondence. Lists of board members., 2 (Folder 17)
- Motorola Executive Institute. Correspondence. Reports, list of library books, clippings and holograph notes., 2 (Folder 18)
- Speeches and Papers: Introductions, final words to graduates and memorial resolutions (Vanderbilt University) - Box 5, Folder 38.
  - Introductions:
    - Introduction of Lord Halifax to Duke University audience, ca. 1940.
    - Introduction of Dr. Mims, Neely Auditorium, Jan. 1948.
    - Introduction of John Foster Dulles, June 4, 1950.
    - Introduction of Arthur Hays Sulzberger as conmencement speaker, (1950).
    - Introduction of David Kaser, Nashville Rotary Club, Dec. 5, 1961.
    - Introduction of Charles Frankel, Friends of the Library dinner meeting, 1978.
  - Undated:
    - Introduction of the Very Reverend George M. Alexander.
    - Introduction of O.C. Carmichael, President's Commission on Higher Education.
    - Introduction of Don R. Elliott, Rotary Club.
    - Introduction of Andy Holt, Rotary Club.
    - Introduction of Dr. Virgil Melvin Hancher of the University of Iowa.
    - Introduction of Major General Jen Lin Huang, Class of '22.
    - Introduction of Dr. Edward McCready.
    - Introduction of Dr. John S. Millis, Nurshing School Anniversary dinner meeting.
    - Introduction of Randall Stewart as commencement speaker.
  - Final remarks to graduating class:
    - Commencement, 1950.
    - Commencement, June 8, 1952.
    - Commencement, 1959.
    - Comnencement, 1960.
    - Commencement, June 4, 1961.
    - "Most of you are now leaving academic halls...", n.d.
    - "It is a tradition of this University that before you leave this campus..," n.d.
    - "It is a tradition of this University that before you leave, the Chancellor has the privilege..," n.d.
    - "It is a long established custom.n.d.
    - "Final Word," n.d.
    - "To Graduates," n.d.
    - "No Signs on the Highway," Baccalaureate Address, May 1973.
  - Memorial Resolutions:
    - John Keith Benton (1896-1956). Tributes by the Divinity School Faculty and the Chancellor of the University at a memorial service held in Stockham Memorial Chapel, Nov. 28, 1956.
    - Remarks made at memorial service for Sam Clark, July 3, 1960.
    - Board of Trust memorial resulution honoring Orrin Henry Ingram, May 4, 1963.
    - Remarks made at funeral service for Harold S. Vanderbilt, Trinity Episcopal Church, Newport, Rhode Island, July 7, 1970.
    - Board of Trust memorial resolution honoring Harold Stirling Vanderbilt, 1970.
    - Board of Trust memorial resolution honoring Nathaniel Baxter Johnson, Nov. 9, 1973.
    - Board of Trust memorial resolution honoring Robert Livington Garner.
    - Resolution in memory of Oliver Cromwell Carmichael, Jr., Oct. 22, 1976.
- National Conference on Citizenship« Correspondence. Reports, agendas, lists of members. Articles establishing the National Citizenship Clubs. By-laws. Definition of citizenship. Summary of meeting. Summary of Youth Program., 2 (Folder 19)
- Planned Parenthood Association of Nashville. Correspondence. Reports, lists of members. By-laws, minutes of Board Directors' Meeting., 2 (Folder 20)
- Robert A. Taft Institute of Government. Correspondence. Report, printed invitation., 2 (Folder 21)
- State, Department of. Correspondence., 2 (Folder 22)
- Tennessee Botanical Gardens and Fine Arts Center. Correspondence, lists of board members, reports on aims and objectives., 2 (Folder 23)
- Tennessee Higher Education Commission. Correspondence. Paper on "The Competent College Student.", 2 (Folder 24)
- Tusculum College. Correspondence. Lists of board members. Reports: The Academic Scene at Tusculum. Report of the Governance Committee on the Future of Academic Programs at Tusculum College Statement of Purpose, 1977., 2 (Folder 25)
- UNESCO, 1963-64. Correspondence. Reports, agendas, lists, notes and printed materials: Printed messages from the President of the United States; membership rosters, papers on Freedom of Expression in the Arts; Report on U.S. National Commission, Financial and Staff Resources; Texts of Human Rights Conventions on Slavery, Forced Labor, Political Rights of Women and Genocide; UNESCO and Education; "Report on UNESCO" by Harvie Branscomb published in Bulletin on International Education; "Progress Report on UNESCO" published in Saturday Review; Report of the U.S. Delegation to the 13th General Conference of UNESCO; Report to the Carnegie Corporation on "The Universities of South and East Africa"; Bangkok Conference of Asian National Commissions; holograph notes; trip itineraries; travel notes on a visit to Asia., 3 (Folder 26)
- UNESCO, 1964-65. Correspondence. Reports: Some problems related to what extent we emphasize foreign students coming here or sending teachers abroad; Some suggestions for a United States position on the problem of the free flow of information; UNESCO after 20 Years; Reports of the U.S. Delegation; Recommendations for the UNESCO program; membership lists., 3 (Folder 27)
- UNESCO, Minutes and Actions. Reports: Soviet Cultural Influence in North Korea; Objectives; Executive Committee reports on Privileges and Immunities Requirement Bars UNESCO-sponsored Meetings in U.S.,and UNESCO and American Universities - Follow-Up Program., 3 (Folder 28)
- U.S. Advisory Commission. Correspondence. Remarks at Seventh Annual Birthday of the Americas Dinner; Trip itineraries; Report on European Trip, Summer 1949., 3 (Folder 29)
- U.S. Public Health Council. Correspondence. Reports, agendas, lists and resolutions., 3 (Folder 30)
- Urban League and Race Issues. Correspondence. Minutes, lists of board members, by-laws, printed materials., 4 (Folder 31)
- Vanderbilt University. Board of Trust Committee on the Succession to the Chancellorship. Correspondence., 4 (Folder 32)
- Vanderbilt University. Documents and Assorted Papers. Correspondence. Papers, reports, agendas and printed materials., 4 (Folder 33)
- Vanderbilt University. Lawson Affair. Correspondence. Printed articles: "Is Civil Disobedience the Way?" by Harvie Branscomb, "A Policy the University Can Defend" by Robert McGaw, "Vanderbilt's Time of Testing" by J. Robert Nelson, "The Lawson- Vanderbilt Affair, Letters to Dean Nelson," Statement; of Principles and Procedures to be followed in Cases of Student Discipline wherein Issues of Academic Freedom are Raised., 4 (Folder 34)
- Reports: Statement made by Harvie Branscomb at the Arts and Science Faculty Meeting on March 8, 1960; Statement made by Dr. Quillian to the Student Body at Assembly on Jan. 3, 1961; Recommendations of the Beach Committee appointed to recommend procedures to be followed in the future; Proposed White Paper on "The Lawson-Nelson Case at Vanderbilt University"; "Some Comments and Reflections on the Lawson Episide." Newspaper clippings., 4 (Folder 34)
- Vanderbilt University. Statue of Harold S. Vanderbilt. Correspondence. Papers and printed materials. Photograph., 4 (Folder 35)
- World Bank Project. Correspondence. Reports., 4 (Folder 36)
- World Health Organization. Correspondence. Reports: Committee on International Health to the National Advisory Health Council; Committee on Progranme and Budget, Provisional Minutes of the Fifteenth Meeting; Draft Sixth Report of the Committee on Programme and Budget; Extension of WHO Activities-Research; Health Aspects of World Population; Some Questions and Comments Concerning the Program of the WHO More Particularly in the Field of Education and Training. Holograph notes, lists of members, travel authorizations., 4 (Folder 37)
- Draft of Board of Trust memorial resolution honoring Gertrude Conaway Vanderbilt, 1978.
- Board of Trust memorial resolution honoring William Oscar Jenkins. Remarks made at memorial service for Charles Robinson.
  - Speeches and Papers: Vanderbilt University - Box 5, Folder 39.
- Address to Vanderbilt Alumni, Fall 1946.
- Founder's Day Speech, May 27, 1948.
- Honors Day Speech, May 3, 1950.
- Remarks to the Nashville Soliciting Team, McTyeire Hall, Sept. 6, 1950.
- "The State of the University." Report of the Chancellor to the Alumni, Sept. 1, 1950.
- Seventy-fifth Anniversary speech, Oct. 21, 1950.
- "State of the University." Sept. 18, 1951.
- Address at New York luncheon honoring Grantland Rice, Nov. 1, 1956.
- Address at the Fugitives'Reunion, (1956).
- Address at Alumni luncheon, 1957.
- Welcome address at Medical School Symposium, 1958 or 1959.
- Statements made by Chancellor Branscorab in presenting Board of Trust citations, Oct. 17, 1959.
- Remarks at the Dedication of the W.R. Wills Center for Psychiatric Treatment and Research, Jan. 6, 1961.
- Speech at Veterans Administration Hospital Cornerstone Laying Ceremony,: June 19, 1961.
- Welcome to new students, Sept. 13, 1961.
- Speech to the Faculties, Sept. 15, 1961.
- Address to the Vanderbilt AAUP, Oct. 2, 1961.
- Final speech to the Faculties, Sept. 14, 1962.
- Speech to the Living Endowment Area Chairmen, Vanderbilt University, Nov. 16, 1962.
- Remarks by Dr. Branscorab at dinner, Feb. 7, 1963, given by Mr. and Mrs.
- Harold Vanderbilt honoring Mr. and Mrs. Alexander Heard.
- Working notes on the contributions of Harold S. Vanderbilt during the period, 1946-63.
- "A Janus View," Vanderbilt Alumnus.
- "UNESCO after 20 Years." Forum, Vanderbilt University, March 31, 1966.
- Remarks on the occasion of the Reunion of the Vanderbilt Family at Vanderbilt University, March 17, 1973.
- Remarks at Dedication of Bust of Eldon Stevenson, May 4, 1973.
- Suggested remarks submitted to Mr. Sam Fleming, re: installation of Dr. TeSelle as Dean of the Divinity School, August 13, 1975.
- Address at program honoring Bill Darby, Nov. 1979.